<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Gabriel Maja</title>
    <link>https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Gabriel Maja</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Climate Change Belief Analysis (tweet sentiment)</title>
      <link>https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>This Project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub Repository
For this project I was assigned to a team of 5 individuals. We then decided to allocate 2 Project Managers as co-leaders for this project. Myself and another individual took on this role. We made use of external tools (to ensure the success of this project) such as:
 Trello (project management) Streamlit (model deployment) Comet (version control) MS Powerpoint (project presentation)  A basic project breakdown and the steps we followed can be found below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: South African Language Identification (Classification Hackathon)</title>
      <link>https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This Project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub Repository
(Image credit)
 In this hackathon, I was tasked with creating a model that takes text (as input) which is in any of South Africa&amp;rsquo;s 11 official languages. This model must then identify which language the text is in. I started off with some basic EDA (Exploratory Data Analysis) to get an idea of the state of the data – which I found to be quite clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Spain Electricity Shortfall Challenge</title>
      <link>https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabe-maja.github.io/data-science-portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>This Project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub Repository
 In this project, my team (consisting of 5 individuals) was tasked to model the shortfall between the energy generated by means of fossil fuels and various renewable sources - for the country of Spain. The team decided that I take on the position of Project Manager. The load_shortfall_3h (3-Hour Daily Shortfall) was modelled as a function of various city-specific weather features such as pressure, wind speed, humidity, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
